Kevin Andres



Software Engineer

Software engineer with 4+ years of enterprise experience in full-stack development, mainly using Java/NodeJs and ReactJs while participating in the complete product development lifecycle within Agile teams. Specializing in backend development and micro-services architecture on cloud services.

Animated by well-designed code and discovering new business problematics; Interested in SaaS, Blockchain, Finance and Data analysis.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Backend

Jul 2020 - Present

Stey - social & lodging industry

Beijing - China

Responsible for the backend development within micro-services architectures of +20 services written in Kotlin and Scala. Use of Azure cloud, Azure CI, Kubernetes, SpringCloud and event streams with Kafka.

- · Creation and design of new API modules as micro-services
- Housekeep operations management system designed under Akka & Kafka event streams
- Tencent SMS & Chat API integration
- IOT third-parties APIs integration for connected rooms
- · new digital invoices & contracts management
 - WeChat & Alipay APIs for mobile payment; transactions tracking and reporting
 - · legal E-signing, automatic billing, IOT locker, PDF generation
 - kotlin first PDF generation library based on generic grid design including a markdown interpreter
- Migrate Hibernate JPA to Exposed, refactor services to SOLID principles

Full-Stack Developer

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020

Scottish Power - Energy industry

Glasgow - Scotland

- Migrate ASP.Net websites to React web-apps following PWA norms. Achieving 100 scores on Lighthouse including push-notifications, cache, offline mode, and optimizations on ReactJs. Creation of an inhouse CMS.
- Webapp in React & Redux to display electricity data and shortcuts from all over the UK
- Responsible for designing and developing a complete Push-Notification administration ecosystem
 - RestAPI (Spring) managing push notifications and events triggered by third party services
 - Webapp (React) with Kerberos login to administrate notification streams and manage data reports
 - Successfully designed prototypes and deployed to production on JBoss with APIs behind WSO2
- Supervision and mentor of an intern for the development of chatbots on NodeJs with IBM Watson

Software Developer

Jan 2018 - Nov 2018

Linnworks - E-commerce industry

Portsmouth - England

Devevelop new features to tackle e-commerce & warehouse. Promoting customer-centric approach.

- Implement webapps using .Net & Angular for e-commerce & warehouse custom management
- C# pluggins using linnworks SDKs to expand the core-product's functionalities through our marketplace
- Custom automated SQL reports for customers
- Integration of third-party APIs for Global-E and Magento2 for shipping functionalities

EDUCATION

Epitech - European Institute of Information Technology

Jul 2012 - Dec 2017

Master Information Technology

Paris

Beijing Jiaotong University

Sep 2016 - Jun 2017

Master Software Engineering

Beijing

SKILLS LIST

French native; English professional; Chinese beginner

- Language: Java, Kotlin, Solidity, JavaScript, Scala, C++, Go
- Back-End: RestAPI, micro-services, Blockchain, Spring Boot/Cloud/Security & Kerberos, Lagom, Akka, Kafka, Play, Express.js, Maven, Redis, Zipkin, Swagger, JUnit, Mockito
- Front-End: ReactJs, Web3, AngularJS & Angular, Html & CSS, Bootstrap
- DB & Tools: SQL, MongoDB, Elastic Search, Exposed, Hibernate & JPA, Slick, Mybatis
- Tools: Truffle, Etherum, Kubernetes, Azure, Git, NodeJs, Nginx, JBoss, AWS, Jira, Docker, Windows/Linux